Oh
this will sound pretentious and I don't
mean it to sound pretentious so bear
with me I don't really think you can
understand Taoism if you don't engage in
a Taoist practice you'll bring the wrong
meanings to terms right I mean Taoism is
like making love or swimming you don't
really understand it until you do it
right if you talk about it you never
done it you're going to misunderstand it
well what I started do is I started
practicing Tai Chi and then I've learned
five forms of Tai Chi I did some chi
khong right things like that some e
chuan janjong all of these practices and
then then I started reading people like
you know like you know Alan Watts had a
lot on Taoism will the watercourse way
dowas in the way beyond seeking things
like that but I I can't emphasize enough
my first point if you don't do these
practices right your understanding of
this stuff is going to be sort of
seriously skewed because I've seen that
sort of in I mean I don't have any you
know academic evidence but I've got a
lot of sort of anecdotal evidence that
people get it only after they're doing
the practice for Buddhism I mean there's
lots of good books on it I would
recommend the same thing I would
recommend if you want to understand
Buddhism that in addition to reading
your no real poulos book and what the
Buddha taught or some of the books like
that you also take up some of the books
on meditative practice and you know
cornfield and gold steam they have a
series of books on the past no
meditation that are excellent so not
only do they teach of the Buddhist
philosophy they take you they teach you
the practice that gives you the actual
you know you have to taste this you have
to really love it too in this sense i'm
talking about here to understand it you
have to know it by loving it if i can
actually offer one more i mean those are
all amazing scituate suggestions for the
down aging which is loud so the
fundamental yeah text it comes up Taoism
a guy called Steven Amos did a
translation on one of the earliest texts
that's available if you're looking for
kind of an intellectual framework I mean
as Jon says it's it's very much an
experiential thing but if you're looking
for kind of an intellectual framework to
approach it from his philosophical
translation really I think that is
probably the best expo
I've seen he's a highly respected
academic in the East Asian Studies field
he's taught at the University of Beijing
so even the Chinese themselves respect
the way he approaches it so again guy
one thing to that if you're going to
read don't just with that I don't real
out say don't not read loud say but if
you're going to read aloud to say read
shuang's or two absolutely okay you need
to read both like chocolate and peanut
butter two great tastes that go together
you